welcome to another darktable tutorial in
欢迎来到中的另一个暗表教程
this video we'll learn how to apply
这个视频我们将学习如何应用
masks to our images so it's just a basic
面具到我们的图像 所以这只是一个基本的
intro to using masks and what masks lets
口罩使用简介和什么口罩可以
us do is mask out a certain part of the
我们所做的就是遮盖住
image and apply different modules or
映像并应用不同的模块或
effects to only that part of the image
仅对图像的该部分产生影响
masks can be very simple shapes or very
面具可以是非常简单的形状或非常
complex and we'll learn how to do those
复杂 我们将学习如何做到这一点
in this video I have images here I've
在这个视频中 我有一些图像
downloaded from we saturate calm I'm
下载自我们饱和平静我是
going to use this one for our example
在我们的示例中将使用此示例
you can download this and follow along
您可以下载此文件并进行后续操作
I'll include the link in the description
我会在描述中包括链接
of this video if you want to follow
如果你想关注这段视频
along in this tutorial with this exact
与本教程中的完全相同
image so over here to the left we have
图像在左边 我们看到的是
our history and I had a step that I
我们的历史和我有一步 我
applied here that I'll be showing you
在这里应用 我将向你们展示
how to recreate basically the only thing
如何重现基本上唯一的东西
I've done here is applied the monochrome
我在这里所做的是应用单色
module and then I've masked out just
模块 然后我已经屏蔽了
this part a simple circle around the eye
这部分是围绕眼睛的一个简单的圆圈
we can see what that looks like this
我们可以看到它是什么样子的
mask and it's doing a drawn mask right
面具 它正在画一个正确的面具
here and it's just a circle hope there's
在这里 这只是一个圆圈 希望有
a second one so we could apply this a
第二个 这样我们就可以将这个应用到
second time if there were two eyes we
第二次 如果我们有两只眼睛
could have the other eye over here but
可能另一只眼睛在这里 但是
we see everything within this circle is
我们看到这个圈子里的一切
not being affected and everything
不受影响和一切
outside of the circle is being affected
圈子之外的人正在受到影响
by this monochrome and that's because we
单色 那是因为我们
have it inverted down here at the bottom
把它倒过来放在这里的底部
but we're getting ahead of ourselves
但我们有些超前了
let's just undo this whole thing so
让我们把这整件事都取消吧
we'll turn this off and actually we'll
我们会把它关掉 实际上我们会
just come over to this base we'll go
只要到这个基地来 我们就走
back one step in history and hit
在历史上后退一步 击中
compress history stack so it's as if
压缩历史堆栈 使其看起来
that never happened now and then also
这从来没有发生过 有时也是如此
under our mask manager I'm just gonna
在我们经理的掩护下 我只是想
right click and go clean up unused
右键单击并清理未使用的内容
shapes so this is how yours will look
所以这就是你的造型
under mask manager you'll have no shapes
在遮罩管理器下 您将没有形状
and you'll just be left with this stock
你只剩下这只股票了
image and monochrome is if we enable it
图像和单色是如果我们启用它的话
it just goes over the whole thing so I'm
它只是检查了整个过程 所以我
gonna show you from the very start how I
从一开始我就会告诉你我是如何
created that look so what we need to do
创造了这样的外观 所以我们需要做的是
first is draw a mask there's a few ways
首先是画一个面具 有几种方法
to do it what we can do is come over
要做到这一点 我们所能做的就是过来
here to our mask manager this shows us
给我们的面具经理 这向我们展示了
all the different masks that we create
我们创造的所有不同的面具
and we can jump back to a mask if we
我们可以跳回面具 如果我们
ever want to use it multiple times so
有没有想过要多次使用它
the different ways to draw we can hover
我们可以悬停的不同画法
over and see what options we have here
过来看看我们这里有什么选择
we have add brush we can add a circle
我们有添加笔刷 我们可以添加一个圆圈
and ellipse a path or a gradient and so
并对路径或渐变进行椭圆等操作
for this one I did a circle but what the
对于这个我做了一个圆圈 但这是什么
brushed
已刷牙
it lets us just draw so we can
它让我们只画画 这样我们就可以
left-click and everything in black is
左键单击 黑色的所有内容都是
what's going to be affected so we can
什么会受到影响 这样我们就可以
kind of draw in a brush but that's not
有点像画笔 但那不是
perfect for the eye it looks like a
完美的眼睛 它看起来像一个
bunch of lines but if we were to apply
一堆台词 但如果我们要申请
this it would give kind of the same
这一点它也会给出同样的东西
effect it's just not as accurate as we
它只是不像我们所说的那样准确
would want ctrl Z will undo that what I
会想要Ctrl Z来撤销我所做的
used was the circle and so if we do the
使用的是圆 所以如果我们这样做
circle and then we click it creates a
圆圈 然后我们点击它创建一个
circle we can use our scroll wheel
圆圈 我们可以使用滚轮
inside of the circle to change the size
在圆圈内更改大小
the scroll wheel on the mouse or we can
鼠标上的滚轮 或者我们可以
scroll well in here between to change
在此处滚动以进行更改
the size of the feather and if we just
羽毛的大小 如果我们
left click and drag we can move it
左键点击并拖动 我们就可以移动它
around so we'll move this to the center
所以我们要把这个移到中间
of the eye and then we'll make the
然后我们将制作
feather kind of go out to here
羽毛有点像是从这里出来的
or maybe we'll click and make this size
或者我们可以点击一下 把这个尺寸
go out to here and then the feather will
走到这里 然后羽毛就会
come in to about there that's probably
大约在那里 这可能是
good and the feather is just going to be
很好 羽毛将会是
fade a kind of a fade for the mask so
淡出一种面具的淡入淡出
it's not just such a harsh hard cut over
这不仅仅是一次如此严酷的割伤
from the effect it makes it look more
从效果来看 它看起来更像是
natural or less obvious that a module is
模块是自然的或不太明显的
being applied okay now what we have in
现在我们的应用很好
our manager we have two brushes we have
我们的经理我们有两把刷子
this one that we created and then we
这是我们创造的 然后我们
have this one that we created so we can
有我们创建的这个 这样我们就可以
use either one that we want and we could
使用我们想要的任何一个 我们就可以
do a third if we want we can click on
如果我们想做第三个 可以点击
this path and the what the path lets us
这条路和这条路给我们带来了什么
do is left-click and every time we click
DO是左键点击 每次我们点击
it creates a node so we can do a much
它创建了一个节点 因此我们可以做很多事情
more advanced shape so I'm just left
更高级的造型 所以我只剩下
clicking around this entire eye right
在整个眼睛周围点击向右
now and when I'm done I can double click
现在 当我完成后 我可以双击
I was out to do it no what do you do oh
我是出去做的 不 你会怎么做哦
you right click right click to get out
你右击右击即可退出
of it so I've kind of messed that up a
所以我把它搞砸了
little bit we can come in now and and
我们现在可以进来一点 然后
just left-click these and adjust them
只需左键单击这些选项并进行调整
individually to get just the shape we
为了得到我们想要的形状
want and again it has a feather as well
想要 又一次 它有羽毛
we can hover over in between the the
我们可以悬停在
actual shape and the dotted line to
实际形状和虚线设置为
adjust the feather or we can click on
调整羽毛 或者我们可以点击
the inside the actual shape and adjust
内部的实际形状和调整
the size of the whole thing we've drawn
我们画的整幅画的大小
two by just rolling that scroll scroll
两次只需滚动卷轴即可
wheel in and out we can left-click and
轮子进出 我们可以左键点击和
move the whole shape around too and we
也移动整个形状 我们就可以
can adjust these individual nodes they
可以调整这些单独的节点
also have a handle on them who want to
也能控制那些想要
adjust like the bow we can do a little
像弓一样调整 我们可以做一点
adjust the curve and the angle of the
调整曲线和角度
node but that's maybe something we'll do
节点 但这可能是我们要做的事情
more in the next tutorials so all we've
在接下来的教程中有更多内容 所以我们所拥有的
really done is drawn masks we're not
真正做完的是我们没有画出面具
working with any modules right now we
现在我们正在使用任何模块
can apply these three masks that we've
可以使用这三个面具 我们已经
drawn to any modules we want so let's
吸引到我们想要的任何模块 所以让我们
come over to that monochrome one and
走到那个黑白的 然后
let's apply monochrome now so we just
现在让我们应用单色 所以我们只是
enable it by clicking here and it
通过单击此处启用它 然后
applies this monochrome module to the
将此单色模块应用于
entire image we've done this sort of in
整个图像我们都是这样做的
the past we can move this around and
过去 我们可以改变这一切
sort of change the way that that it's
某种程度上改变了它的方式
interpreting and and looking at those we
解释和观察那些我们
can adjust this on/off aggressing much
可以很有侵略性地调整这种开/关
in this particular image but we can
在这张特殊的图像中 但我们可以
still make all the different settings we
仍然做着我们所有不同的设置
want to change the entire image but if
想要更改整个图像 但如果
we only want this module and its
我们只想要这个模块及其
corresponding settings to apply to
要应用到的相应设置
what's inside of our mask we need to go
我们的面具里有什么 我们需要去
to this blend under here where it says
到这下面的混合体 上面写着
blend right now it says off so we drew a
现在混合 它说关闭 所以我们画了一个
drop down here and it says what do you
放在这里 它会说你想做什么
want to do uniformly which is what we're
想要统一地做 这就是我们
actually doing now we can click on that
实际上 现在我们可以点击它
uniformly just means it applies it to
统一只是意味着它将其应用于
the entire image evenly or we can do a
整个图像均匀 否则我们可以
drawn mask which is what we want to do
画面具 这就是我们想要做的
because we drew some masks here we'll
因为我们在这里画了一些面具
cover these other ones later we have
稍后我们将介绍这些其他的
parametric masks and drawn and
参数蒙版和绘制的和
parametric masks we'll do those ones
我们将做这些参数遮罩
later but for now just do drawn masks
以后 但现在只做画好的面具
and then we can we have these same tools
然后我们可以我们有这些相同的工具
down here that we can draw a mask we
在这里 我们可以画一个面具 我们
could do a circle and ellipse a path use
可以做一个圆和一个椭圆的路径使用
the brush it's the same tools that we
刷子和我们用的工具是一样的
have over here on our mask manager and
在我们的面具管理器上
if we draw a mask over here if we do
如果我们在这里画一个面具 如果我们这样做
like the ellipse and we draw any lips it
就像椭圆一样 我们画出任何嘴唇
appears over here in our mask manager as
在我们的掩码管理器中显示为
well so there's multiple tools we have
所以我们有多种工具
for drawing them I just want to show you
为了画它们 我只是想让你看看
can draw from the mask manager and so
可以从掩码管理器中绘制 因此
now we see what happened with that
现在我们来看看发生了什么
ellipse it applied the monochrome just
椭圆它只是应用了单色
where that ellipse was so we can change
那个椭圆在哪里 这样我们就可以改变
the size of this and anywhere this shape
它的大小和这个形状的任何地方
is at it will be where our effect is
就是它将是我们的效果所在
being applied we kind of want that to
我们有点想把它应用到
look a little bit different don't we
看起来有点不同 不是吗？
because we don't we I showed you earlier
因为我们不知道我之前给你看过了
it wasn't a black and white eye it was a
那不是黑白的眼睛 而是一只
colored eye and everything else black
有色眼睛和其他所有黑色的东西
and white to invert the mask we just
白色来反转面具 我们只是
click over here
请点击此处
we hover over this little line this
我们在这条小线上盘旋
little icon with a circle with a line
带圆圈和线条的小图标
through it is called toggle polarity of
通过它被称为切换极性
the drama
戏剧性的
if we click that then it toggles and so
如果我们点击它 它会切换 所以
now is the opposite so now we see the
现在是相反的 所以现在我们看到
color and everything else is a black and
颜色和其他所有东西都是黑色的
white if we want to do we can now if we
白色 如果我们想做 我们现在就能做 如果我们
click over here right now we're using
点击此处 我们现在正在使用
the shape called ellipse number four but
这个形状叫做四号椭圆 但是
we can change to use something different
我们可以改用不同的东西
so we if we look over here under drawn
所以我们 如果我们看着这张图
mask there's a drop down and we could
面具有一个下拉列表 我们可以
use this brush number one instead that
用这把1号刷子代替那个
we drew earlier which is pretty much the
我们早些时候打出了平局 这几乎是
same effect we could use this circle
同样的效果 我们可以使用这个圆圈
which is also going to be pretty much
这也将是相当大的
the same effect or we could use our oh
同样的效果 或者我们可以用我们的哦
we want it we don't want to use all
我们想要它 我们不想用所有的
three we want to use one or the other
三个 我们想用其中一个
we could use our path number three which
我们可以用我们的第三条路
is that line out here so we have a set
那条线在这里吗？所以我们有一套
up to use all all of them right now if
现在使用所有这些资源 如果
we hover over this we say show and edit
我们悬停在这上面 我们说放映和编辑
mask elements so that just shows if
元素的掩码 以便仅显示
there on there being viewed sometimes
在那里有时会被观看
especially with this one it gets in the
尤其是这一次 它进入了
way so we can toggle to have it be not
这样我们就可以切换到它不是
shown but it's still being affected I'm
但它仍然受到影响 我是
not exactly sure how to remove we've got
不太确定如何删除我们已有的
a bunch of them on now I'm not sure how
一大堆现在我不知道是怎么回事
to remove those so I'm gonna do is go to
去掉那些 所以我要做的就是
reset on here and we'll do the same
在这里重置 我们也会这样做
thing with blend but this time we'll
混合的东西 但这一次我们将
only select one of them so we'll go back
只选其中一个 这样我们就会回去
to drawn mask and we will just use just
到绘制的面具 我们将只使用
one of these masks so let's use just
这些面具中的一个 所以我们只用一个
this circle here and then we'll go to
这个圆圈在这里 然后我们会去
invert so that's really it and then we
倒置 就是这样 然后我们
can we could do the same thing if we
我们能做同样的事情吗？如果我们
didn't want to do monochrome or we could
我不想做单色 或者我们可以
leave the monochrome on and now we can
让单色保持打开 现在我们可以
grab another one like maybe what should
再来一杯 也许应该是什么？
we do this color contrast if we go to
我们做这种颜色对比 如果我们去
color contrast now and enable color
立即启用颜色对比度和启用颜色
contrast if we make changes it's going
相反 如果我们做出改变 它就会发生
well since everything is black and white
既然一切都是黑白分明的
this kind of convenient for us but we
这对我们来说很方便 但我们
can go to our blend mode we can go to
可以进入我们的混合模式我们可以进入
drawn mask and just do again this circle
画好面具 再画一次这个圆圈
number two and now the changes that we
第二 现在我们的变化是
make well we can change sort of the
希望我们可以改变一些
color of that eye we can make it look
那只眼睛的颜色 我们可以让它看起来
like a different color or more extreme
喜欢不同的颜色或更极端
if that circle is bothering us we can
如果这个圈子困扰着我们 我们可以
turn off seeing it but still apply
看不见它 但仍然适用
changes to it and if we ever want to
它的变化 如果我们想要
make changes we can come over here to
做出我们可以到这里来的改变
our mask manager and click on that
我们的面具管理器 然后点击
circle number two and then we can make
第二个圆圈 然后我们就可以
changes to it we can move
对它的更改我们可以移动
around we might have to reapply it over
我们可能不得不重新使用它
there if we do that though oh no it's
如果我们这样做了 哦 不 这是
going you just took a second
你刚走了一秒钟
so it'll then make those changes to
因此它将对其进行这些更改
wherever we move it to on the image we
无论我们在图像上将其移动到哪里 我们
can even change the size of it we can do
我们甚至可以改变它的大小
all kinds of stuff so that's basic drawn
所有的东西 所以这是基本的画
masks in the next video we're gonna
在下一个视频中 我们将会
let's touch a little bit more on using
让我们更多地了解一下使用
the paths tool to draw our mask and then
路径工具绘制我们的蒙版 然后
also we're going to be looking at
另外 我们还将看到
parametric masks as well so go ahead and
参数遮罩也是如此 因此请继续
play with those if you want to get
如果你想得到的话就玩吧
something undone we right click we can
我们可以用鼠标右键点击未完成的事情
go ctrl Z to undo things in darktable
按Ctrl Z键撤消暗表中的内容
but I think I'm going to leave this
但我想我还是留下这个吧
video here and then of course like we've
视频在这里 当然 就像我们
learned in the past if you want to
从过去学到的东西如果你想
export this if we love the way this
如果我们喜欢这种方式 就把它出口
looks we can just go to light table
看起来我们可以去轻桌了
click on the image and go down to our
点击图片 然后转到我们的
export selected and click export and
导出所选内容并单击导出 然后单击
that will export just the selected image
这将仅导出选定的图像
or any images selected and that goes to
或任何选定的图像 这些图像都将发送到
our folder here in where was that image
我们的文件夹在哪里有那张图片
since that since that was in dest
因为那是在DEST中
downloads it's going to be a new folder
下载将是一个新文件夹
called darktable exported and we have
名为暗桌出口 我们有
just this exported image and again like
就是这个导出的图像 然后再一次
we've talked about before our original
我们在我们的原作之前已经谈过了
image is still here unaffected one of
图像仍然在这里 未受影响的一个
these ones so we don't have to worry
这些 所以我们不用担心
about overwriting our image if we ever
关于改写我们的形象 如果我们
want to get back to the original we can
想要回到原来的我们可以吗？
definitely just do that thanks for
当然 就这么办 谢谢
watching hopefully found this
满怀希望地看着发现了这个
informative go ahead and leave your
见多识广去吧 留下你的
question in the comments below play with
下面评论中的问题玩弄
masking just know that all you'll look
蒙面只知道你会看起来
at all these different modules they all
在所有这些不同的模块中 它们
have this blend option so the sky is the
有这个混合选项 这样天空就是
limit on what you can do you can even do
限制你能做的事情 你甚至可以做
exposure to a specific part of the image
暴露在图像的特定部分
really really powerful stuff play with
非常非常强大的玩意儿
drawn first and once you get comfortable
先画 等你觉得舒服了再画
with that we'll move on to parametric
到此为止 我们将继续讨论参数
thanks for watching guys - catch you in
感谢收看《伙计们》-不见不散
the next tutorial
下一个教程